[
    {
        "question": "The Union Budget 2025-26 has proposed to increase the loans provided through KCC to farmers under the Modified Interest Subvention Scheme to ?",
        "options": [
            "Rs 4 lakhs ",
            "Rs 3 lakhs ",
            "Rs 5 lakhs ",
            "Rs 7 lakhs "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 5 lakhs "
    },
    {
        "question": "The Kisan Credit Card was introduced in India on the recommendation of which committee?",
        "options": [
            "RV Gupta committee ",
            "K. Santhanam Committee ",
            "Abhijit Sen Committee ",
            "Abid Hussain Committee "
        ],
        "answer": "RV Gupta committee "
    },
    {
        "question": "Nyokum Yullo festival is celebrated in which state of India?",
        "options": [
            "Manipur  ",
            "Arunachal Pradesh  ",
            "Nagaland  ",
            "Assam "
        ],
        "answer": "Arunachal Pradesh  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state government has launched an accidental insurance scheme for school children named Shiksha Sanjeevani Bima Yojana?",
        "options": [
            "Assam ",
            "Bihar  ",
            "Rajasthan  ",
            "Uttar Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Rajasthan  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which insurance company will administer the Shiksha Sanjeevani Bima Yojana of the Rajasthan government?",
        "options": [
            "Zurich Kotak General insurance ",
            "Aviva Life Insurance ",
            "Bajaj Allianz Life Insurance ",
            "Aegon Life Insurance "
        ],
        "answer": "Zurich Kotak General insurance "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank has sanctioned a loans to the tune of Rs 1,500 crore for Self Help Group (SHG)?",
        "options": [
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank  ",
            "Indian Overseas Bank  ",
            "Indian Bank  ",
            "Canara Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Indian Bank  "
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city is the Gopinath Bordoloi International Airport located, whose new terminal building design was recently unveiled?",
        "options": [
            "Varanasi ",
            "Lucknow ",
            "Guwahati ",
            "Shillong "
        ],
        "answer": "Guwahati "
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will the 12th Regional 3R and Circular Economy Forum be held?",
        "options": [
            "Varanasi ",
            "Patna ",
            "Shimla ",
            "Jaipur "
        ],
        "answer": "Jaipur "
    },
    {
        "question": "In which coastal state of India was the Exercise 'Sagar Kavach' conducted on 21-22 February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Gujarat ",
            "Tamil Nadu ",
            "West Bengal ",
            "Maharashtra "
        ],
        "answer": "West Bengal "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who inaugurated the 8th Madhya Pradesh Global Investor Summit 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Draupadi Murmu  ",
            "Narendra Modi  ",
            "Amit Shah  ",
            "Rajnath Singh "
        ],
        "answer": "Narendra Modi  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the 4th Badminton Asia Mixed Championship 2025 title?",
        "options": [
            "Qatar  ",
            "India ",
            "Indonesia  ",
            "Japan "
        ],
        "answer": "Indonesia  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Saurav Ghosal defeated which player to win the PSA Octane Sydney Classic 2025 Squash Tournament?",
        "options": [
            "Abdelrahman Nassar ",
            "James Willstrop ",
            "Jesse Engelbrecht ",
            "Paul Coll "
        ],
        "answer": "Abdelrahman Nassar "
    },
    {
        "question": "Where did Prime Minister Narendra Modi release the 19th Installment of the PM-KISAN scheme?",
        "options": [
            "Bhagalpur, Bihar ",
            "Gaya, Bihar  ",
            "Nawada, Bihar  ",
            "Aurangabad, Bihar "
        ],
        "answer": "Bhagalpur, Bihar "
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term of the newly appointed 11th Chairman of Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI), Tuhin Kanta Pandey?",
        "options": [
            "2 years ",
            "3 years  ",
            "4 years  ",
            "5 years "
        ],
        "answer": "3 years  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which post was held by Tuhin Kanta Pandey before he was appointed the Chairman of Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI)?",
        "options": [
            "Foreign Secretary ",
            "Finance and Revenue Secretary ",
            "Cabinet Secretary ",
            "Defence Secretary "
        ],
        "answer": "Finance and Revenue Secretary "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the 11th chairperson of the Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) for a three-year term?",
        "options": [
            "Arvind Virmani  ",
            "V. K. Paul  ",
            "V. K. Saraswat ",
            "Tuhin Kanta Pandey "
        ],
        "answer": "Tuhin Kanta Pandey "
    },
    {
        "question": "SEBI has mandated mutual funds (MFs) to deploy the corpus collected during the new fund offering (NFO) period within how many days?",
        "options": [
            "30 Days  ",
            "20 Days  ",
            "15 Days ",
            "25 Days "
        ],
        "answer": "30 Days  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has assumed the office as the 11th President of the Asian Development Bank?",
        "options": [
            "Masatsugu Asakawa ",
            "Masato Kanda ",
            "Shigeru Ishiba ",
            "Seiichiro Murakami "
        ],
        "answer": "Masato Kanda "
    },
    {
        "question": "How much of the loan has been sanctioned by the Asian Development Bank for the Kolkata Municipal Corporation Sustainability, Hygiene and Resilience (Sector) Project?",
        "options": [
            "$ 200 million ",
            "$ 300 million ",
            "$ 400 million ",
            "$ 500 million "
        ],
        "answer": "$ 200 million "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank has unveiled a new term deposit product, Annuity Deposits, specifically designed for resident customers?",
        "options": [
            "Yes Bank  ",
            "HDFC Bank  ",
            "ICICI Bank  ",
            "Federal Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Federal Bank "
    },
    {
        "question": "NITI Aayog has constituted a committee to prepare a roadmap aimed at transforming AIIMS, New Delhi into a premier institution for medical research and practice. Who is heading this committee?",
        "options": [
            "Jyoti Narula ",
            "Vijay Kumar Saraswat ",
            "Arvind Virmani ",
            "V K Paul "
        ],
        "answer": "V K Paul "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank launched the 9th edition of the Evolve knowledge-sharing seminar for MSMEs?",
        "options": [
            "HDFC Bank ",
            "Axis Bank ",
            "ICICI Bank ",
            "State Bank of India "
        ],
        "answer": "Axis Bank "
    },
    {
        "question": "Power Finance Corporation has inked an initial pact to provide Rs 26,800 crore finance to power utilities of which state?",
        "options": [
            "Uttar Pradesh  ",
            "Himachal Pradesh  ",
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Rajasthan "
        ],
        "answer": "Madhya Pradesh  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank has tied up with World Trade Center (WTC) Mumbai to enhance credit access for small businesses and boost India's exports ecosystem?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai to enhance credit access for small ",
            "Axis Bank  ",
            "Yes Bank  ",
            "HDFC Bank  ",
            "ICICI Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Axis Bank  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank has launched a pilot for a merchant-focused loyalty and cashback programme using programmable central bank digital currency (CBDC)?",
        "options": [
            "? ",
            "Canara Bank  ",
            "Bank of Baroda  ",
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank  ",
            "Yes Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Canara Bank  "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is set to sign agreements with Israel and Saudi Arabia to explore and process critical minerals?",
        "options": [
            "India ",
            "Russia  ",
            "Japan  ",
            "United States "
        ],
        "answer": "India "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is scouting for mining and exploration of critical mineral assets in Congo, Zambia, Tanzania and Australia?",
        "options": [
            "India ",
            "Japan  ",
            "Russia  ",
            "China "
        ],
        "answer": "India "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has introduced the Blue Visa for a 10-year residency permit focused on environmental sustainability?",
        "options": [
            "Saudi Arabia ",
            "Qatar ",
            "Oman ",
            "UAE "
        ],
        "answer": "UAE "
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state in India is home to the highest vulture population?",
        "options": [
            "Uttar Pradesh ",
            "Rajasthan ",
            "Madhya Pradesh ",
            "Bihar "
        ],
        "answer": "Madhya Pradesh "
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the military exercise ‘Jal-Thal-Raksha 2025’ conducted?",
        "options": [
            "Gujarat ",
            "Maharashtra ",
            "Kerala ",
            "Tamil Nadu "
        ],
        "answer": "Gujarat "
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the main goal of the MoUs signed by TRIFED with NIFT and HPMC?",
        "options": [
            "Boost Tribal Entrepreneurship ",
            "Enhance Fashion Design Education ",
            "Promote Horticulture in Himachal Pradesh ",
            "Increase Export of Tribal Products "
        ],
        "answer": "Boost Tribal Entrepreneurship "
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the fund launched to boost biodiversity finance?",
        "options": [
            "Green Fund ",
            "Cons Fund ",
            "Bio Fund ",
            "Cali Fund "
        ],
        "answer": "Cali Fund "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chairman of the Ratan Tata Endowment Foundation?",
        "options": [
            "Jamsheed Poncha ",
            "N Chandrasekaran ",
            "Natarajan Chandrasekaran ",
            "Mehli Mistry "
        ],
        "answer": "N Chandrasekaran "
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the 3rd SABA Women Championship 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Maldives  ",
            "Nepal  ",
            "India ",
            "Sri Lanka "
        ],
        "answer": "India "
    },
    {
        "question": "SABA Women Championship is related to which sport",
        "options": [
            "Tennis  ",
            "Football  ",
            "Badminton  ",
            "Basketball "
        ],
        "answer": "Basketball "
    },
    {
        "question": "When is National Science Day celebrated every year?",
        "options": [
            "26 February ",
            "27 February ",
            "28 February ",
            "29 February "
        ],
        "answer": "28 February "
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the theme of National Science Day 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Empowering Indian Youth for Global Leadership in Science & Innovation for Viksit Bharat ",
            "Future of STI: Impact on Education Skills and Work ",
            "Indigenous Technologies for Viksit Bharat ",
            "Integrated Approach in S&T for Sustainable Future "
        ],
        "answer": "Empowering Indian Youth for Global Leadership in Science & Innovation for Viksit Bharat "
    }
]